# JENS ERNSTBERGER

+49 170-781-7661 \$\display \text{Munich, Germany \$\display jens.ernstberger@tum.de}\$

#### ACADEMIC INTEREST

My main research interest lies in security for decentralized systems, with a recent focus on DeFi security and Data Sovereignty. Beyond that, I am interested in the role of decentralized systems in resource constrained environments. I am most excited about problems that require novel theoretical insights and also have real-world applications.

## **EDUCATION**

## Technical University of Munich

07/2021 -

Research Assistant and PhD Candidate

- Professorship for Embedded Systems and IoT
- Advisor(s): Sebastian Steinhorst, Arthur Gervais

## Technical University of Munich

09/2018 - 03/2021

Master of Science, Electrical Engineering and Information Technology

- Advisor: Sebastian Steinhorst
- Master Thesis: Zero Knowledge Proof of Authorization for DLT-based Identity Management

## Technical University of Munich

08/2015 - 09/2018

Bachelor of Science, Electrical Engineering and Information Technology

• Bachelor Thesis: Teleoperated Control of a Humanoid Robot

## Wilhems-Gymnasium, Stuttgart

09/2007 - 06/2015

High School Diploma

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### University of California, Berkeley

07/2022 - 09/2022

Visiting Researcher – Center for Responsible, Decentralized Intelligence

- Research Fields: Decentralized Identity, Decentralized Access Control, Decentralized Computation
- Collaboration with Imperial College London and Texas AM University

FAS AG 10/2020 - 12/2020

Working Student - Digital Architects

- Support of the Managing Partner through preparation of meetings and project proposals
- Development of Business Intelligence solutions and platform-based data analytics applications

**KPMG AG** 06/2019 - 05/2020

Working Student - Automotive Institute

- Identification of trends in the automotive industry through extensive data analysis
- Content development & conception of a study on the future of the autmotive sector
- Led the Business Intelligence for the study by building more than 50 BI dashboards

## Tsinghua – Daimler Joint Research Center

12/2018 - 05/2019

Research Associate - Digital Hub

- Research on new in-car applications through behavior prediction and customer interaction
- Created a location prediction application for automated destination prediction in China

#### Mercedes-Benz R&D North America

08/2017 - 11/2017

Intern - IoT & Wearables

- Programmed a skill for Amazon Alexa using the Amazon Alexa skills kit & Node.JS
- Implemented new and expanded already existing functions to interact with the vehicle

Daimler AG 03/2017 - 05/2017

Intern – Digital Vehicle & Mobility

- Market analysis of existing digital assistants
- Preparation of presentations for the Top-Management

### **PUBLICATIONS**

2022 'SoK: Decentralized Finance (DeFi) Incidents'

Liyi Zhou, Xihan Xiong, Jens Ernstberger, Stefanos Chaliasos, Zhipeng Wang, Ye Wang,

Kaihua Qin, Roger Wattenhofer, Dawn Song, Arthur Gervais Science of Blockchain Conference (Stanford, August 2022)

2021 'A-PoA - Anonymous Proof of Authorization for Decentralized Identity Management'

Jan Lauinger, Jens Ernstberger, Emanuel Regnath, Mohammad Hamad, Sebastian Steinhorst

IEEE International Conference on Blockchain and Cryptocurrency (ICBC, May 2021)

## TALKS

2022 SoK: Decentralized Finance (DeFi) Attacks

UC Berekeley Center for Responsible Decentralized Intelligence (RDI Lunch Seminar, September 2022)

An Empirical Study of DeFi Liquidations: Incentives, Risks, and Instabilities

The Science of Blockchain Conference, Stanford (August 2022)

Data Sovereignty and Decentralized Data Science

UC Berkeley Haas Institute for Business Innovation (IBI Brown Bag Seminar, July 2022)

#### **SKILLS**

Languages German, English, French, Chinese

**Programming** Advanced in Python, Sufficient in Matlab, Javascript, Go

Tools Git, Docker, Tableau, Powerpoint

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant Software Architecture for Distributed Embedded Systems

Technical University of Munich, Fall 2021

Advanced Seminar Embedded Systems IoT

Fall 2021, 2022; Summer 2022

## **SERVICES**

External Reviewer 2021: FC, AFT

2022: CESC, S&P (Oakland), NDSS, Usenix Security, CCS, AFT, ConsensusDay22

2023: S&P (Oakland), NDSS